Dean Walker's collection on Mount Desert, Maine church records, 1792-1905.
Congregational Library & Archives
Dean Walker's collection on Mount Desert, Maine church records, 1792-1905.
1886 1905
bulk 1886-1905
MS5136
Congregational Library & Archives
0.44 Cubic Feet
(1 box)
Dean Augustus Walker was born in 1860 in Turkey. He attended Yale and the University of Chicago and was married to Mary Ladd Smith in 1896. He was ordained as a Congregational minister in 1901 and served the Mt. Desert Congregational Church of Tremont for three years. His later career focused on teaching various religious and language courses for a number of institutions, including the Syrian Protestant College in Beruit. Walker died in Auburndale, Massachusetts in 1914. This collection is one collected by Walker about the Mt. Desert community and primarily includes correspondence from his time serving it. The bulk of the records span from 1901-1905. He collected printed works by the churches: manuals, orders of worship and informational material.
Tremont Congregational Church (Tremont, Me.)
Walker, Dean Augustus
Restrictions on Access
Access to this collection is unrestricted and open to the public.
Acquisition Information
Original origin of the collection is unknown, but the collection was originally housed in the Congregational Library & Archives non-circulating collection but was moved to the archives in 2013; 2013-30.
Biographical Note
Dean Augustus Walker was born in 1860 in Turkey. He attended Yale and the University of Chicago and was married to Mary Ladd Smith in 1896. He was ordained as a Congregational minister in 1901 and served the Mt. Desert Congregational Church of Tremont for three years. His later career focused on teaching various religious and language courses for a number of institutions, including the Syrian Protestant College in Beruit. Walker died in Auburndale, Massachusetts in 1914.
Scope and Contents
This collection is one collected by Walker about the Mt. Desert community and primarily includes correspondence from his time serving it. The bulk of the records span from 1901-1905. He collected printed works by the churches: manuals, orders of worship and informational material.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Church records and registers.; Clergy -- Correspondence.; Ephemera.; Walker, Dean Augustus; Mt. Desert Congregational Church (Southwest Harbor, Me.); Southwest Harbor Congregational Church (Southwest Harbor Me.)
- Notes and copies of Mount Desert Church record book, 1792 1905; 1792-1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Church ephemera, 1835 1904; 1835, 1899-1904 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Union Church of Northeast Harbor meeting minutes, 1886 1891; 1886, 1891 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1889 1903; 1889-1903 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Correspondence and reports, 1895 1904; 1895-1904 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cranberry Isle letter and article, 1899 1903; 1899, 1903 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newspapers articles, 1902 1903; 1902-1903, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1903 1904; 1903-1904 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, 1904 1905; 1904-1905 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Research notes, 1904 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)